Guide to the Henry T. Bahnson Papers, 1943-2002 UA.90.F82
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Henry T. Bahnson Papers
1943-2002
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Bahnson, Henry T.
UA.90.F82
9.75 Linear Feet (11 boxes)
Henry Theodore Bahnson was the longest serving chairman of the University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine (1963-1987) and a world renowned transplant surgeon. The majority of the collection is made up of correspondence between Dr. Bahnson and his professional colleagues. In addition, the collection contains materials outlining Bahnson's professional and personal achievements, an array of medical slides, and several VHS tapes of surgical procedures.
Biography
Henry Theodore Bahnson was the longest serving chairman of the University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine (1963-1987) and a world renowned transplant surgeon. Born in Winston-Salem, North Carolina in 1920, Dr. Bahnson graduated from Davidson College in 1941. He then traveled to Boston to complete his graduate work at the Harvard University Medical School. After graduation in 1944, Bahnson moved with his wife, Louise Porter, to Baltimore Maryland, where he began an internship in surgery at Johns Hopkins Hospital. While at Johns Hopkins, Bahnson trained with renowned surgeon Dr. Alfred Blalock, one of the pioneers in the field of cardiac surgery. Bahnson spent the early part of his career involved in clinical investigation and introduction of new techniques within vascular and cardiac surgery. Bahnson remained at Johns Hopkins until 1963, eventually achieving the rank of professor within the University.
In 1963 Bahnson accepted the George V. Foster Chairmanship of Surgery at the University of Pittsburgh Medical School. In addition to his personal feats in cardiovascular transplantation – such as performing the first heart transplant in Pennsylvania in 1968 – Bahnson actively recruited leaders within the field of medicine, helping to raise both the University's Medical School and the University's Medical Center to international prominence. Dr. Bahnson is credited with recruiting Dr. Thomas E. Starzl, known by many as the "Father of Transplantation."
While at the University of Pittsburgh, Bahnson served on the surgical staff of UPMC Presbyterian (formerly Presbyterian-University Hospital), Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh, and the Pittsburgh VA Healthcare System. He was president of numerous professional groups during his career: the Society of University Surgeons (1965), the American Association for Thoracic Surgery (1976-1977), the American College of Surgeons (1983-1984), the American Surgical Association (1987-1988) and the Johns Hopkins Medical and Surgical Association (1989-1990). He was also a member of the Society of Thoracic Surgeons, the American Society of Transplant Surgeons, the International Society for Heart Transplantation, and the Transplant Recipient International Organization.
Dr. Bahnson and his wife were the parents of five children. Dr. Bahnson died in his Pittsburgh home in April, 2003.
Scope and Content Notes
The collection is organized alphabetically by subject, in keeping with Bahnson's original organizational scheme. The majority of the collection is made up of correspondence between Bahnson and his professional colleagues, including, but not limited to, Dr. Thomas E. Starzl, Dr. Mark Ravitch, and Dr. Alfred Blalock. The largest single component of the collection is made up of materials relating to Dr. Thomas Starzl. This series includes correspondence between Bahnson and Starzl, correspondence between Bahnson and colleagues about Starzl, and correspondence between Starzl and Dr. Alfred Blalock.
In addition to correspondence, the collection contains materials outlining Bahnson's professional and personal achievements. These include papers relating to the first annual conference about FK-506 (an immunosuppressive drug used to treat transplant patients), a conference for which Dr. Bahnson was personally involved in organizing; and records of his involvement with various professional organizations. The collection contains Bahnson's original research for a paper titled "Roles of the Kidneys in the Resistance of Rats to Hemmorhage," as well as copies of speeches and addresses he gave throughout his professional career. Besides the materials relating to his scientific accomplishments, the collection contains extensive information on Bahnson's musical achievements, such as two harmonicas he designed and patented after conducting studies of the physical reactions of the body while playing the harmonica.
Bahnson worked with physicians and professors from Korea and the USSR, and he worked especially closely with physicians from Vietnam, many of whom he met during his work with medical residents in Saigon in the 1970s. The collection contains correspondence relating to sponsorship, employment opportunities, and funding for these associates.
Finally, the collection includes an extensive array of medical slides assembled by Bahnson over the years, and a series of hand-drawn medical illustrations used in several journal articles, and five VHS tapes which were used as animal lab testing instructional videos. The medical slides include a detailed index, which has been organized by subject headings. A complete alphabetic list of subject headings is included with the numbered index in Box 5. The majority of the medical illustrations were drawn by Leon Schlossberg, a charter member of the Association of Medical Illustrators (AMI), and the recipient of the AMI's lifetime achievement award in 1990.
Access Restrictions
Several files contain private legal, medical or financial information and are subject to various restrictions. Restricted files are identified in the contents list and are contained in Boxes 1-4, 7 and 8. For questions about access conditions, contact the University Archivist. (Box 2 ff 30, 33, 35)
Acquisition Information
Gift of Alfred Blalock Bahnson, son of Henry T. Bahnson, in April 2003.
Previous Citation
Henry T. Bahnson Papers, 1943-2002, UA.90.F82, University Archives, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Business correspondence; Medical illustrations; Color slides; Lectures; Speeches; University of Pittsburgh; Personal correspondence; Faculty papers; Administrative reports; Harmonica; Physicians -- Vietnam; Medical colleges -- Faculty; Academic medical centers -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Heart -- Surgery -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc. -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Medicine -- Study and teaching -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Vietnamese students -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Medical students, Foreign -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Residents (Medicine) -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Cardiologists -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Surgeons -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Physicians -- China; Physicians -- Korea; Health and medicine; Physicians -- Soviet Union; American College of Surgeons; American Surgical Association; Bahnson, Henry T.; Blalock, Alfred; Central Surgical Association; Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh; Ravitch, Mark M.; Schlossberg, Leon; Simmons, Richard L.; Starzl, Thomas E. (Thomas Earl); University of Pittsburgh. School of Medicine
- Subject Files, I.
  - A
    - A (General), 1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Ad-Hoc Honor Code Committee, 1982-1983, 1987-1996 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - American Association of Thoracic Surgery (AATS), 1976-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - AATS Ad Hoc Committee Past Presidents, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - American College of Surgeons (ACS), 1984-2002 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - American Surgical Association (ASA), 1994-2002 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - ASA - Presidency, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Animal Surgery Lab, 1995-1996 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annals of Surgery, 1995-1998 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Annals of Thoracic Surgery, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Archives of Surgery, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Australia - Visits, 1955-1983 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - B
    - B (General), 1965-2002 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - "Bahnson Day", 12-13 March 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Bahnson Development Fund, Endowed Professor, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Bahnson Hosted Social Events, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Bahnson Visiting Professor Lectureship, 1991-2002 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Bahnson, Henry T. - Acceptance of position at Dept. of Surgery University of Pittsburgh, 1961-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bahnson, Henry T. - Awards, Biographical Info., 1968-1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Bahnson, Henry T. Curriculum Vita [RESTRICTED] (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Bahnson, Henry T. - Personal [RESTRICTED], 1963-2001 (Box 1, Folder 21-22)
    - Bahnson, Robert, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Bethune, Dr. Norman - Note on The Scalpel, the Sword, The Story of Dr. Norman Bethune (available in the University Library System), undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Blalock, Dr. Alfred, 1941-1988 (Box 1, Folder 25-26)
    - Bockeria, Dr. Leo, 1996-2002 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - British TV Program, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - C
    - C (General), 1989-2002 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Carey, Dr. Larry C., 1969-1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Central Surgical Association, 1969-1989 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Children's Hospital of Pittsburgh, 1988-1993 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Chinese Visiting Doctors, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - CHIRURGIE 2000, Paris, France, June 25-29, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Clinical Use of Total Body Hypothermia", Southwestern Cardiovascular Symposium, March 20, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Committee for Oversight Organ Transplantation, 1992-1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Cooley, Dr. Denton A., 1951-1972 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - D
    - D (General), 1989-1999 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Davidson College, 1981-1991 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Davis & Geck Tapes and Lab Manuals, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - DeBakey Award, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - DeBakey, Dr. Michael E., 1954-1997 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - DeBakey Lectures (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Department of Surgery, 1995-2001 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Department of Surgery Research Endowment Campaign LAY Committee, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Detre, Dr. Thomas P. [RESTRICTED], 1984-1991 (Box 1, Folder 46-47)
    - "Development of the Transplantation of the Heart" -China Speech, October 1992 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    - Dzung Quang Le, M.D., 1989-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - E
    - E (General), 1961-1992 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Eiseman, Dr. Ben, 1949-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - F
    - F (General), 1990-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Falkowski, George, 1991-1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Falor Society Dinner (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Fellowships, 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - FK-506 Conference [RESTRICTED], 1990-1991 (Box 2, Folder 8a-8b)
    - Fung, John, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - G
    - G (General), 1986-2002 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Governance Issue between University of Pittsburgh School of Medicine and Affiliated Hospitals, 1976-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Graduation Speeches, 1973-1993 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Gramlich, Dr. John B., 1964-1996 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Gross, Dr. Robert E., 1952-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - H
    - H (General), 1987-1999 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - The Halstead Society, 1989-1996 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Harbison, Dr. Samuel P., 1962-1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Harmonica, Correspondence and Patent Information, 1989-2002 (Box 2, Folder 18-19)
    - Heart to Heart, 1992-2000 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - H.J. Heinz Foundation, 1990-1992 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - I
    - Insurance (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - International Society for Heart Transplantation, 1986-1993 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - International Surgical Group, 1957-2001 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - International Conference on the History of Cardiovascular Surgery (2nd: Moscow), November 2002 (Box 2, Folder 24a)
  - J
    - J (General), 1989-1997 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Jing Hua, 1988-1995 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Johns Hopkins Medical and Surgical Association, 1990-1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - K
    - K (General), 1990-1994 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Kemp, Charles, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Kosela vs. Singh, Restricted, 1989-1993 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      Access Restrictions
      This file is restricted.
  - L
    - L (General), 1990-2000 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Ladowski, Joseph, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Legal File, [RESTRICTED], 1988-1993 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Licenses [RESTRICTED], 1989-1998 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Louise P. Bahnson Research Fellowship, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - M
    - M (General), 1990-2000 (Box 2, Folder 36)
    - Mexico Talk - Ethics (Box 2, Folder 37)
    - Meyers, Dr. Jack, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - Minute Men of the Medical School, 1988-1999 (Box 2, Folder 39)
    - Montefiore Hospital, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Moscow - talk, November 16-21, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Miller, Harry - Tribute, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - N
    - N (General) [RESTRICTED], 1990-1997 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Nam Ky Van, 1994-1997 (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - T, XIV.
      - Task Force on Curriculum Revision, 1991-1992 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Tran, Huong Thien, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Transplantation - Resources, Matas Memorial Lecture, December 14, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Transplant Recipient International Organization, Inc. (TRIO), 1991-1997 (Box 4, Folder 01-02)
      - Traveling Professors speech about Alfred Blalock, Baylor University, Dallas, TX, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
        Scope and Content Notes
        Correspondecne with Sparkman.
      - Trento, Alfredo, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - Trips to China, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - O
    - O (General), 1996-1999 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - P
    - P (General) [RESTRICTED], 1984, 1990, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    - Pham Family, 1974-1987 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    - Pittsburgh Surgical Society - Talk, May 18, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    - Presbyterian University Hospital (PUH) [RESTRICTED], 1984-1990 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - Presbyterian University Hospital, Transplantation Discussions, Bahnson, Starzl, Hakala, [RESTRICTED], 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Publications (Box 3, Folder 4a)
      Practical Guide in Surgical Techniques for Medican Students by Mary C. Mancini 1983, rev. 1992 by Henry T. Bahnson.
      U SA-Russia Tweny Years of Cooperation in Cardiopulmonary Research, 1972-1992.
      Bakoulev Scientific Center for Cardiovascular Surgery of Russian Academy of Medical Sciences, L.A. Bockeria
  - R
    - R (General), 1990-1999 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Ravitch, Mark; Correspondence, 1952-1987 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
    - Ravtich, Mark; Memorial Information [RESTRICTED], 1989-2000 (Box 3, Folder 8-10)
    - Residency, School of Medicine, 1992-1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Resident Alumni Association, 2000-2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Rocky Mountain Traumatologic Society, 1984-1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Roles of the Kidneys in the Resistance of Rats to Hemorrhage", 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - S
    - S (General) [RESTRICTED], 1976-1999 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Schwentker, Frederick N., 1993-1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Schumacker, Jr., Dr. Harris B., 1953-1988 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Simmons, Dr. Richard L., 1988-1995 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Society of Clinical Surgery; Photographs (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Includes photographs of Thomas Starzl
    - Society of Clinical Surgery (Box 3, Folder 19a)
    - Starzl, Dr. Thomas E.; letters of support, 1977-1998 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Starzl, Dr. Thomas E.; Controversies, 1981, 1992-1994, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Starzl, Dr. Thomas E.; Correspondence, 1959-1995 (Box 3, Folder 22-26)
      Includes correspondence on on Puzzle People
    - Starzl, Dr. Thomas E.; Curriculum Vita and General, 1960-1999 (Box 3, Folder 27-28)
    - Starzl, Dr. Thomas E.; History of Transplantation speech given at UCLA, March 1999 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Starzl, Dr. Thomas E.; Recruitment to Pitt, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - Steichen, Dr. Felicien M.; Selected Essays From Minimally Invasive Surgery and New Technology, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - Substitute Hearts; Speech for the ASC meeting, New Orleans, October 20, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - T
    - T General (Box 3, Folder 32a)
    - Task Force on Curriculum Revision, 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Tran, Huong Thien, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Transplantation Resources, Matas Memorial Lecture, December 14, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - Transplant Recipient International Organization, Inc. (Trio), 1991-1997 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Traveling Professors, Negative Feedback from Alfred Blaylock, Baylor University, Dallas, TX, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Trento, Alfredo, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Trips to China, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - U
    - United Way Campaigns, 1996-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - USSR - Correspondence with Associations, 1987-1991 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - V
    - Veterans Administration Hospital, 1989-1996 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Vietnam Refugee Physicians, 1973-1988 (Box 4, Folder 9-11)
    - Visiting Professors, China, 1987-1995 (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
    - Visiting Professors, Korea (Chong Kook Lee), 1989-1995 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Visiting Professors, USSR (Chebotar, Anatoli and Moshnyaga, Andrew ), 1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - W
    - W, 1990-1994 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Watson, 1991-1995 (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - W.L. Gore and Associates, Inc., 1985-1992 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Z
    - Z, 1993-1997 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Z Legal - Tracy Lynn Gauden Trial [RESTRICTED], 1986-1993 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Medical, II.
  The Medical Slides are arranged by subject number. The subject index is contained in the three boxes called "Card Index to Slides"
  - Medical Slides (Box 4, Folder 22, Slide 5-527)
  - Medical Slides (Box 4, Folder 23, Slide 527-552)
  - Medical Slides (Box 4, Folder 24, Slide 552-650)
  - Medical Slides (Box 4, Folder 24, Slide 650-655)
  - Medical Slides (Box 4, Folder 26, Slide 656-669)
  - Medical Slides (Box 5, Folder 1, Slide 670-707)
  - Medical Slides (Box 5, Folder 2, Slide 708-736)
  - Medical Slides (Box 5, Folder 3, Slide 744-817)
  - Medical Slides (Box 5, Folder 4, Slide 817-925)
  - Medical Slides (Box 5, Folder 5, Slide 925-975)
  - Medical Slides (Box 5, Folder 6, Slide 976-980)
  - Medical Slides (Box 5, Folder 7, Slide 980-999)
    Separated Material
    The last page of this file contains slides from subjects 655, 744, 925 and 975.
  - Medical Slides Subject Index (Box 5, Folder 8-10)
  - List of Subject Headings (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - "Cholecystectomy" (Box 6, Cassette 1-1a)
  - "Historical Perspective on Stapling in Surgery" by Mark M. Ravitch (Box 6, Cassette 2)
  - "Small Bowel Resection" by Thomas B. Julian (Box 6, Cassette 3)
    Recording does not begin until one quarter of the way into the tape.
  - "Fundamental Surgical Techniques" by Larry Carey (Box 6, Cassette 4)
  - "Splenectomy" by David L. Steed (Box 6, Cassette 5-5a)
  - "Cecectomy" by Thomas B. Julian (Box 6, Cassette 6)
    Video appears to be partial procedure.
- Illustrations, III.
  - Aneurysm to be excised - Leon Schlossberg (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Atrial spatial defect - Leon Schlossberg (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Defect / Defect closed - Leon Schlossberg (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - R. atrial appendage - Leon Schlossberg (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Aortic aneurysm - Leon Schlossberg (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30 IV) Fig. 30-2 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30 V) Fig. 30-6, "Treatment of ductus arteriosus by division" (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Sabiston &Spencer (Bahnson - 30 V) Fig. 30-5, "Operative treatment of ductus arteriosus by ligation" (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30 IV) Fig. 30-3, "Tracheal ring completed by obliterated remnant of distal left arch and ligamentum arteriosum" (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Fig. 9, 12, Bahnson, Journal of Thoracic Surgery (Box 7, Folder 10-11)
  - Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30 VII) Fig. 30-11, "Operative exposure for resection of the coarctation of the aorta" (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Postductal, Preductal, Interrupted Aorta (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30X) Fig. 30-34, Leon Schlossberg (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30 VII) Fig. 30-12, "Anastmosis following excision of coarctation" (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Case 1, Fig. 1C - Leon Schlossberg, undated (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Fig. 5 Bahnson, Journal of Thoracic Surgery, Leon Schlossberg (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Illustrations- Eddie Williams (1) (Oversize) (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Illustrations- Abdominal Aneurysm (1) - Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Illustrations- Lung, Aorta - Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Illustrations- McLeod (3) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Illustrations- Ventricular septal defect - Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Illustrations- Case 6, Fig. 6e, "Aneurysm of the aorta and in-nominate artery", Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Illustrations- Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30 IV) Fig. 30-1, "Development of the aortic arch and anomalies", undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Illustrations- Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30X) Fig. 30-36b, "-Excision of the fusiform aneurysm of the ascending aorta", undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Illustrations- Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30X) Fig. 30-35, "Aneurysm of the upper thoracic aorta treated by proximal and distal aortic occlusion, excision, and aortic reconstruction" (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Illustrations- Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30X) Fig. 30-41, "Inclusion technique of replacement of thoracic aorta as described by Crawford et. al." (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Illustrations- Sabiston & Spencer (Bahnson - 30X) Fig. 30-39, "Replacement of aortic arch as described by Crawford et. al" (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Illustrations- Aneurysm of the Arch of Aorta - Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Illustrations- A-B LeFevre (Box 10, Folder 13-14)
  - Illustrations- Tumor - Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Illustrations- Fig. 23-22B, Gisson (2) - Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Illustrations- Liver (1-6) - Leon Schlossberg (Box 10, Folder 17-22)
  - Illustrations- Fig. 7a-7b, 12-13, Bahnson, Journal of Thoracic Surgery - Leon Schlossberg, undated (Box 10, Folder 23-26)
- Photos, IV.
  - Bahnson Images (professional) (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Health Sciences Review Photo Shoot, David Aschkenas photographer, Spring 1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - 7th Annual Bahnson Lecture Images (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - American College of Surgeons, Past Presidents Luncheon (2000), Harmonica Photos, Unidentified Event Photos (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Bahnson Group Images (Group and Function Unknown) (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Professional Colleagues and Early Photos (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Equipment Photos (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Vacation Photos (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - CHIRGURIE 2000 Conference Photos, June 2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Charles G. Watson Surgical Education Center Photo (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Board of Thoracic Surgery - Dallas Dinner Photos, April 1973 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Partial list of Department of Surgery Group Photos and Chief Residents (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Surgical Study Section A, April 1974 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Department of Surgery - Group and Individual Photos, 1963-1991 (Box 6, Folder 14-40)
  - Unidentified Images (Box 6, Folder 41)